usefultools.com 2015-06-23

# LiveAnswer - Privacy Policy

_Latest update: January 02, 2014_

This privacy policy applies to [www.LiveAnswer.com](https://www.liveanswer.com/) owned and operated by LiveAnswer. This privacy policy describes how LiveAnswer collects and uses the personal data you provide on our Website: [www.LiveAnswer.com](https://www.liveanswer.com/). It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal data and how you can access and update this information.

LiveAnswer has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Website, [www.LiveAnswer.com](https://www.liveanswer.com/).

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe [here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

## Personal Data

The Personal Data and Browser Data (hereinafter collectively referred to as "Data"), automatically collected from this website (hereinafter the "Site"), by means of automated systems or freely entered by the User, are collected for the purposes, and processed, as follows below.

## Kinds of Data

The Data that may be collected by this Site are name, surname, address, phone number, email, credit card number, IP address and other Data relating to the User's identity or technical access to the Site by the User.

The Browser Data referring to the technical use of the Site must be collected, and transfer is not optional. The User may freely provide the remaining Data, including personal information, unless it is expressly indicated otherwise.

Failure to process certain Data (e.g. contact details, or addresses, or data concerning behavior or user preferences, etc.) may make it impossible for the Site to provide its services.

If the User utilizes the Site to publish or otherwise share Personal Data with third parties, he or she assumes full responsibility: the User states possession of the right to communicate or disclose personal data to third parties, and that they have received prior information thereto, thus relieving the Site of all responsibility for their improper use following disclosure or dissemination.

## Tracking Technologies

#### 1st Party Cookies

We use cookies on this site. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personal data you submit while on our site.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. Session ID cookies are used to make the LiveAnswer platform experience streamlined and easy to navigate. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies may be used for remarketing efforts. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's “help” directory.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.

#### 3rd Party Cookies and Web Beacons

Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers may use both session ID and persistent cookies so that we may provide the services outlined on our site. The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers is covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies.

Our third party partners employ clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), images, and scripts that help them better manage content on our site. We do not tie the information gathered to our Customers' or Users' personal data.

#### Analytics/Log Files

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We do not link this automatically-collected data to personal data. 

#### Behavioral Targeting

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests.

If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads,you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

## The Use of the Collected Data

We collect your Data only for the following purposes:

  * The Provision Of The Service
  * a response to specific requests for information by the User
  * a User update on new products or services provided by the Site or concerning particular business offers
  * the User to be informed of any Site maintenance or inconvenience
  * any commercial profiling of the User
  * to display banners related to User interests (behavioral targeting / advertising)
  * defense by the Website Owner, in court or in the stages leading to possible legal action, against improper use of the same or related services by the User.

Some forms of processing (sending promotional information, commercial profiling, behavioral advertising, etc.) may require the express consent of the User or the Interested Party.

Specific information may be shown on the pages of the Site in connection with particular services or processing of Data provided by the User or by the Interested Party.

## Information Sharing

LiveAnswer processes the Data of the Interested Parties and Users in a lawful and proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification or unauthorized destruction of the Data. Processing is carried out using computers and / or telematic means, with organizational methods and logics strictly related to the stated purposes. In addition to the owner, in some cases, access to the Data may be available to personnel involved in the organization of the Site (administrative, commercial, marketing, legal, system administrators) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Managers by the Owner of the Processing procedure. The updated list of Managers can be requested from the Owner by contacting the above address at any time.

The Data are processed at the headquarters of the LiveAnswer. Any processing of Data outside one of the EU Member States may require the consent of the User or the Interested Party.

LiveAnswer will share your Data with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy as required to provide the services outlined. We do not sell your information to third parties.

We may also disclose your Data:

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request,
  * if LiveAnswer is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal data, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal data,
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so

## Service Providers

We may provide your Data to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as sending you emails. These companies are authorized to use your Data only as necessary to provide these services to us.

## User Access and Choice

The User or the Interested Party can always ask for removal of information from the servers of the Site for legitimate reasons by logging into their online account or contacting us at [info@LiveAnswer.com](mailto:info@liveanswer.com).

If the Data of the User changes, User may also update, amend or delete inaccurate data by making the change in the User's account or emailing us at [info@LiveAnswer.com](mailto:info@liveanswer.com).

## Data Retention

The Data are kept for the time necessary to perform the service requested by the User. We will retain and use the information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Security

The security of all Data collected is important to us. When Users enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [Email Address].

## Legal information

This privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of cookies.

## Links to 3rd Party Sites

This privacy policy applies solely to the Site and is not meant to refer to other sites whose links are possibly contained therein. If you submit any Data to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

## Social Media Features

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook and Twitter button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Changes to this Policy

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, you may contact us at: 

LiveAnswer   
1101 Brickell Avenue   
South Tower Suite 800   
Miami, FL, 33131   
305-514-0159
